♪In the face of turmoil♪
♪面对混乱♪
♪Your roots hold firmly♪
♪你的根牢牢地扎根♪
♪To this piece of land♪
♪为了这片土地♪
♪Chasing after the waves♪
♪追逐海浪♪
♪My leaves flutter across♪
♪我的树叶飘舞♪
♪The horizon♪
♪地平线♪
♪Gazing from afar♪
♪远远眺望♪
♪At the end of the world♪
♪世界的尽头♪
♪Is eternity♪
♪是永恒♪
♪When we meet and then part♪
♪当我们相遇又分离♪
♪When we rely on each other and then drift apart♪
♪当我们互相依赖 然后渐行渐远♪
♪I have never forgotten♪
♪我从未忘记♪
♪As the glinting of swords cut♪
♪剑刃闪烁♪
♪Through the mottled sky♪
♪穿过斑驳的天空♪
♪The falling dreams♪
♪坠落的梦想♪
♪Shatter in the wind♪
♪随风破碎♪
♪As the wind breaks through the waves♪
♪当风破浪时♪
♪It watches thousands of sails cross♪
♪它看着万千帆影交叉♪
♪The vast land and the boundless sea♪
♪广阔的土地和无边的海洋♪
♪Armor and red robes flying high♪
♪铠甲与红袍飞扬♪
♪In the face of bitterness, intense emotions, and joyful adventure♪
♪面对辛酸、 强烈的情感、愉快的冒险♪
♪I only wish you to be by my side♪
♪我只希望你能在我身边♪
♪Making the most of what life offers♪
♪充分利用生活所提供的一切♪
♪Like towering trees with interconnected roots, I'll accompany you to the ends♪
♪就像根相连的参天大树一样 ，我会陪你走到尽头♪
♪Watching fireflies land on our shoulders♪
♪看着萤火虫落在 我们的肩上♪
♪No regrets, no doubts in this world♪
♪这个世界没有遗憾，没有怀疑♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=爱的仙境=
=Episode 11=
=第11集=
Cui Li, why are you blocking me?
崔莉，你为什么挡住我？
Collaborating with the enemy,
与敌人合作，
collaborating with the Zhenxi Army.
与镇西军合作。
Why?
为什么？
Are you not going to confess?
你不打算坦白吗？
Do you have any evidence?
你有证据吗？
This is a secret letter from Li Ni
这是李妮的一封密信
of the Zhenxi Army wrote to you.
镇西军给你写信了。
You gave the Zhenxi Army
你给了镇西军
every detail of the situation of the besieged Yingzhou.
瀛州被围的情况一一详述。
The letter is crystal clear.
信上写得一清二楚。
How did you get your hands on this letter?
你是怎么得到 这封信的？
Why?
为什么？
You're finally admitting it now.
现在你终于承认了。
It's rock-solid evidence.
这是铁证如山。
If it weren't for you,
如果不是你
we didn't have to
我们不必
hand over Luoyang City to the Zhenxi Army.
将洛阳城交给 镇西军。
Arrest her!
逮捕她！
Stop it!
停下来！
Shiqi, you're finally back.
Shiqi, you're finally back.
Did anything happen?
有什么事情发生吗？
We received an urgent military report.
我们收到一份紧急军事报告。
Li Jun and Li Lai and their troops
李军、李来和他们的部队
are closing into Luoshui.
正在逼近洛水。
It looks like
看起来像
Sun Jing has long withdrawn his men
孙靖早已撤回了手下
from besieging my brothers.
以免围攻我的兄弟。
Those two brothers of mine
我的那两个兄弟
sure don't disappoint me.
一定不要让我失望。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Lin, you're here just in time.
林，你来得正是时候。
I've long suspected
我早就怀疑
that Lieutenant He has been contacting Li Ni from the Zhenxi Army in secret.
何中尉一直 在暗中联系镇西军的李妮。
It was she
原来是她
who leaked many of our military secrets.
谁泄露了我们的许多军事机密。
This is the evidence.
这就是证据。
It was Lieutenant He
原来是何中尉
who leaked the news about Yingzhou being besieged.
是谁泄露了瀛州被围的消息。
It was the reason
原来是这个原因
we had to surrender Luoyang City.
我们只得投降洛阳城。
If Lieutenant He doesn't die,
如果何中尉不死的话
how can we face the soldiers
我们该如何面对士兵
who have fought valiantly on the battlefield?
谁曾在战场上英勇作战？
Lin,
林,
I know you have a soft heart.
我知道你有一颗柔软的心。
So,
所以，
let me handle this for you.
让我为你处理这件事。
So, you don't have to worry.
所以，你不必担心。
Guards!
卫兵！
Stop it!
停下来！
Cui Li,
Cui Li,
Taozi wrote this letter.
桃子写下了这封信。
Young Master is aware of this matter as well.
这件事，少爷 也知道。
Recently, Lieutenant He noticed unusual activity
最近，何中尉注意到 异常活动
within the army.
军队内部。
After she reported this to me,
当她向我报告此事后，
she deliberately wrote this letter as bait
她故意写这封信作为诱饵
to see
查看
who would fall for it.
谁会上当。
You set me up.
你算计了我。
The letter is in my camp.
这封信在我的营地里。
If you didn't send someone to steal it
如果你没有派人来偷的话
because of your malicious intent,
因为你的恶意，
how would it have ended up in your hands?
它怎么会到 你手里呢？
Lin, I...
林，我...
I did this
我做了这个
because she's behaving very suspiciously.
因为她的行为 非常可疑。
I only wanted to assist you.
我只是想帮助你。
You have to believe me.
你必须相信我。
I was only trying to...
我只是想...
Father trained
父亲受训
the Cui Army.
崔军。
Our soldiers are united
我们的战士是团结的
and follow a strict military code.
并遵守严格的军事法规。
We've never had any internal conflicts
我们从来没有发生过任何内部矛盾
or power struggles.
或权力斗争。
Cui Li, since you arrived,
崔莉，自从你来了之后，
you've repeatedly tried to frame your comrades!
你屡次试图 陷害你的战友！
Do you think
你认为
I didn't notice
我没注意到
your little schemes and ideas?
你的小计划和想法？
When one frames his comrade,
当一个人陷害他的同伴时，
what is the punishment according to the Cui Army's regulations?
按照崔军的规定，处罚是什么？
Those who frame comrades will be stripped of their military power
陷害同志者 ，将被剥夺军权
and receive thirty strokes.
并受到三十次鞭打。
Cui Li, your five thousand soldiers
崔立，你的五千士兵
will be temporarily commanded by Shu.
暂时由蜀指挥。
Since this is your first offense,
既然这是你第一次犯错，
we'll skip the rod punishment.
我们将跳过棍棒惩罚。
Lin...
林...
Go!
去！
This time, we managed to take the opportunity to reclaim Cui Li's military power.
这次我们趁机 夺回了崔立的兵权。
I believe
我相信
he can't stir up any trouble now.
他现在不能惹任何麻烦。
Young Master,
少爷，
are you all right?
你没事儿吧？
Did you catch a cold from staying outside too long?
你是不是因为在外面待太久而感冒了？
I'll have Taozi come
我让桃子来吧
and check your pulse.
并检查你的脉搏。
Ying,
英，
where did you go
你去哪儿
when you left the camp today?
你今天什么时候离开营地的？
I went to see Li Ni.
我去看李妮了。
Li Ni is the commander of the Zhenxi Army!
李妮是 镇西军统帅！
You shouldn't have gone and met him privately multiple times!
你不应该 私下里见过他多次！
I know
我知道
you don't want to hear me say this right now.
你现在不想听我说这个。
But
但
as you saw today,
正如你今天所看到的，
we set up a trap,
我们设置了一个陷阱，
waiting to lure the snake out of its hole.
等待着把蛇 从洞里引出来。
You went out on your own
你一个人出去了
and gave Cui Li a chance to intercept you.
给了崔立 拦截你的机会。
What if he had really attacked you?
如果他真的攻击你怎么办？
Don't worry, Young Master.
别担心，少爷。
A mere Cui Li
为了单纯的崔莉
can't do anything to me.
不能对我做任何事。
Ying,
英，
I know you're confident and prepared.
我知道你有信心并做好准备。
But things are unpredictable in a fight.
但在战斗中，事情是难以预测的。
If you had gotten hurt for real,
如果你真的受伤了
how could I feel at ease?
我怎么能安心呢？
Young Master, here.
少爷来了
Have some tea.
喝点茶。
Drink it.
喝吧。
Are you feeling better?
你感觉好些了吗？
Ying,
英，
do you know something?
你知道什么吗？
You mean more to me
你对我来说更有意义
than anything else.
比其他任何事情都重要。
Even...
甚至...
Even more than myself.
甚至比我自己还要多。
We grew up together.
我们一起长大。
I've always regarded you as an older brother.
我一直把你 当作哥哥。
So, you're also important
所以，你也很重要
to me.
大部头书
Yes,
是的，
we share a sibling-like bond.
我们有着兄弟般的感情。
Saying these
说这些
unexpectedly...
不料...
Unexpectedly makes us feel distant.
没想到让我们感到疏远。
The physician has instructed
医生已指示
that you need a quiet rest.
你需要安静的休息。
So, I won't bother you anymore.
所以，我不会再打扰你了。
Get some rest.
休息一下。
All right.
好的。
At the latest, tomorrow,
最迟，明天，
Li Jun and Li Lai will lead their troops to arrive in Luoyang.
李俊、李来将率兵 抵达洛阳。
Those two
那两个
have always been jealous
一直很嫉妒
of your military achievements.
你的军事成就。
They must have come
他们一定来了
with ill intentions this time.
这次是恶意的。
Shiqi, make up a plan.
Shiqi, make up a plan.
Since my brothers have come,
自从我的兄弟们来了之后，
we should leave
我们应该离开
and give up Luoyang City
并放弃洛阳城
to them.
给他们。
Give up Luoyang City to them?
把洛阳城让给他们？
We fought hard
我们奋力拼搏
to take Luoyang.
to take Luoyang.
And we even gave up three cities
我们甚至放弃了三个城市
in exchange for the withdrawal of the Cui Army from Luoyang.
以换取 崔军撤出洛阳。
Now, do we just hand it over to them?
现在，我们就把它交给他们吗？
It's the same if my brothers are stationed
兄弟们驻扎也一样
in Luoyang City.
in Luoyang City.
Quick and decisive action is essential.
迅速而果断的行动 至关重要。
We'll head to Tong Pass.
我们将前往通关。
How can it be the same?
怎么会一样呢？
(Tong Pass)
（通关）
I get it now.
我现在明白了。
Tong Pass is strategically located with the Wei River to the north,
潼关地理位置优越 ，北临渭水，
Mount Qinling to the south,
南边是秦岭，
Central Plains to the east, and Guanzhong plain to the west.
东边是中原， 西边是关中平原。
Plus, it controls the post road between Xichang and Luoyang.
此外，它还控制着西昌和洛阳之间的驿道 。
It's highly contested military ground.
这是一个竞争激烈的军事基地。
Sun Jing won't expect us
孙静没想到我们
to abandon Luoyang.
to abandon Luoyang.
This will catch him off guard.
这会让他措手不及。
Once we occupy Tong Pass,
一旦我们占领了潼关，
it's like holding Xichang at its throat.
这就像扼住西昌的咽喉一样。
Then, we'll be close
那么，我们就会很接近
to capturing Xichang.
攻克西昌。
That would be the best.
那是最好的。
As long as we hold Tong Pass,
只要我们守住了通关，
those brothers of yours won't have anywhere to advance
你那些兄弟 不会有进步的地方
or to retreat even if they want to take any action.
即使他们想 采取任何行动，也会撤退。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
I thought
我想
you would go soft
你会变得软弱
on those two.
关于那两个。
It's good
很好
to see you're not.
看看你不是。
I'm just looking out for my two older brothers.
我只是在照顾 我的两个哥哥。
They tend to be overly ambitious
他们往往过于雄心勃勃
and easily get carried away.
并且很容易得意忘形。
It's better to let them stay in Luoyang City.
还不如让他们留在洛阳城。
Lest they fall into any traps,
免得他们落入任何陷阱，
and I have to go through great trouble to rescue them.
而我却要费尽千辛万苦 才能把他们救出来。
Young Master.
少爷。
Young Master, you're awake.
少爷，你醒了。
Where's Lieutenant He?
何中尉在哪里？
She stayed in her tent all night
她在帐篷里呆了一夜
and didn't go out.
并没有出去。
Young Master,
少爷，
the physician has checked on you.
医生已经对你进行了检查。
He said you fainted twice.
他说你晕倒过两次。
You must worry less,
你一定要少一些担心
and focus on your recovery.
并专注于您的康复。
I know you're worried about Lieutenant He.
我知道你很担心何中尉。
But sooner or later,
但迟早，
she'll know you're the nicest person to her in the world, Young Master.
她会知道你是世界上对她最好的人 ，少爷。
She's so intelligent.
她很聪明。
Of course, she could feel
当然，她能感觉到
how well I treated her.
我对她有多好。
Then, you should feel at ease even more.
那么，你应该会更加安心。
Lieutenant He isn't an ungrateful person.
何中尉并不是忘恩负义的人。
Yesterday, you went to her rescue despite being ill.
昨天，你冒着病去救她。
Seeing that,
看见那个，
she'll definitely feel moved.
她一定会感到感动。
But what I want from her
但我想从她那里得到什么
is never her gratitude
从来不是她的感激之情
or repayment.
或还款。
Master, stop drinking.
主人，别再喝酒了。
You haven't slept all night.
你一整晚都没有睡觉。
It's harmful to your health.
这对你的健康有害。
Cui Lin, you cunning fox.
崔琳，你这个狡猾的狐狸。
You teamed up with Lieutenant He to trick me
你和何中尉联手来骗我
and forced me to hand over my military authority!
还逼我 交出军权！
It seems
它似乎
they're already suspicious of me now.
他们现在已经开始怀疑我了。
It won't be easy to act
行动并不容易
in the future.
将来。
Master, we just received a secret report.
主人，我们刚刚收到 一份秘密报告。
The Zhenxi Army sent a letter to Lieutenant He again.
镇西军再次给何中尉送信。
Does Cui Lin know about this?
崔琳知道这件事吗？
The secret letter was delivered directly to Lieutenant He's tent.
密信直接送到了 何中尉的帐篷里。
The main camp is unaware of it.
主营对此并不知情。
So,
所以，
should we send someone to investigate?
我们是否应该派人去调查？
After what happened yesterday,
经过昨天的事情之后，
Lieutenant He may lower their guard.
何中尉可能会放松警惕。
We may never know
我们可能永远不知道
if we find something.
如果我们找到什么东西。
As long as Cui Lin is here,
只要崔琳在，
it won't be easy
这并不容易
to take action against Lieutenant He.
对何中尉采取行动。
But if we can discover
但如果我们能够发现
any information,
任何信息，
it would be to our advantage.
这对我们有利。
So
所以
order someone to investigate
命令某人调查
the content of the secret letter.
密信的内容。
Don't leave any trace.
不要留下任何痕迹。
(During my spare time,)
（闲暇时，）
(I often admire personal artwork.)
（我经常欣赏个人艺术作品。）
(I'm currently creating artwork diligently.)
（我目前正在 努力创作艺术品。）
(Is it possible for me to ask for a beautiful portrait of you,)
（请问可以给 你拍一张漂亮的肖像吗？）
(so I won't feel lonely?)
（这样我就不会感到孤独？）
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
aren't you going to reply to the letter?
你不回信吗？
Why are you rushing?
你为什么这么着急？
No, I'm not rushing.
不，我不着急。
The letter isn't for me.
这封信不是写给我的。
Since you're not in a rush,
既然你不着急，
so I'll handle some official documents first.
所以我先处理 一些官方文件。
You can go back and get some rest.
你可以回去休息一下了。
You don't have to keep me company.
你不必陪着我。
I'm not in a hurry.
我不着急。
But Xie Chang'er who delivered the letter
但 送信的谢嫦儿
is in a rush.
很匆忙。
It's such a hot day.
这天真热啊。
He probably has gone back already.
他大概已经回去了。
You don't know
你不知道
how stubborn that person is.
那个人是多么的固执。
If you don't notify him that you're not replying to the letter,
如果你不通知他 你不会回复这封信
he'll definitely still be waiting outside.
他肯定还在 外面等着。
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
I'll go and inform him, then.
那我去通知他一下。
I'm going now.
我现在就去。
I'm going for real.
我真的要去
I...
我...
Wait.
等待。
Since you're in a rush,
既然你很着急，
I'll just write one to reply to his letter.
我就写一封 来回复他的信。
Lest our little Miss Taozi
免得我们桃子小小姐
made a trip for nothing.
做了一次无谓的旅行。
All right.
好的。
I'll wait for you.
我会等你的。
Lieutenant He, the scout reported
侦察员报告何中尉
that the Zhenxi Army had withdrawn from Luoyang.
镇西军已撤出 洛阳。
Lord Liang's eldest son, Lord Linzi, Li Jun,
Lord Liang's eldest son, Lord Linzi, Li Jun,
has led his troop into the city.
已率军入城。
By tonight,
到今晚，
Lord Liang's second son, Lord Kuaiji, Li Lai,
Lord Liang's second son, Lord Kuaiji, Li Lai,
will also arrive with his troops.
也将带着他的军队抵达。
All right.
好的。
I didn't expect
我没想到
Imperial Grandson to be so accommodating
皇孙 竟然这么包容
to his two older brothers.
给他的两个哥哥。
He agrees to whatever they want.
他们想要什么他都同意。
But Lieutenant He,
但是何中尉，
where will he go
他会去哪里
after leaving Luoyang?
离开洛阳后？
Did he mention it in his letter?
他在信中提到过吗？
Of course, he won't mention it in the letter.
当然，他不会 在信中提及此事。
If he didn't mention it in the letter,
如果他在信中没有提到的话
what do you all write about then?
那么你们都写些什么呢？
Only some trivial matters.
只是一些琐碎的事情。
(Please draw it yourself.)
（请自己画。）
Hello, Miss Taozi.
你好，桃子小姐。
A letter our Lieutenant to His Highness.
我们的中尉给殿下的一封信。
Thank you, Miss Taozi.
谢谢桃子小姐。
I'll get going, then.
那我就先走了。
Are you leaving just like that?
你就这样离开吗？
Is there anything else?
还有别的事吗？
What's this?
这是什么？
This is a special healing ointment I personally formulated.
这是我亲自配制的特殊治疗药膏 。
You can't buy it outside.
外面买不到的。
I thought,
我想，
with all your military activities,
以及你所有的军事活动，
there might be
可能有
some bumps and bruises.
一些颠簸和瘀伤。
If you use this,
如果你使用这个，
you'll recover quickly.
你会很快康复的。
Thank you, Miss Taozi.
谢谢桃子小姐。
You're a nice person.
你是一个好人。
Stop talking nonsense.
别废话了。
I'll get going then.
那我就走了。
Thank you!
谢谢你！
What a fool.
真是个蠢才。
(Last night, I stayed in the countryside.)
（昨晚， 我住在乡下。）
(The moon was as clean as if it was washed.)
（月亮干净得像 被洗过一样。）
(I felt like I could pluck the stars from the sky.)
（我感觉我能把 天上的星星摘下来。）
(A few days ago, I visited Zhuque Lane in Dongdu)
（前几天 去了东都朱雀巷）
(and bought some dried fruits.)
（还买了一些干果。）
(They tasted delicious.)
（它们尝起来很美味。）
(They broke like fine jade as I chewed them)
（我咀嚼它们时，它们像美玉 一样碎了）
(and enjoyed chewing them through the long night.)
（并且喜欢 在漫长的夜晚咀嚼它们。）
(I hope to share this experience with you.)
（我希望能与大家分享这段经历。）
♪A fated relationship♪
♪命中注定的关系♪
♪Yet, playing roles that shouldn't be♪
♪然而却扮演着不该扮演的角色♪
(I found combining dried nuts with preserved fruits)
（我发现将干坚果 和果脯结合起来）
(enhances the flavor.)
（增强风味。）
(People in the past enjoyed them separately.)
（过去的人们 分别享受它们。）
(But trying them together now,)
（但现在尝试将它们放在一起，）
(the taste is intriguing.)
（味道很有趣。）
♪Cut off resentment and hatred♪
♪斩断怨恨♪
♪This colorful array across the sky♪
♪天空中绚丽多彩的阵列♪
♪Belongs only to you and me♪
♪只属于你和我♪
♪You're the dawn of anticipation, hearts aglow♪
♪你是期待的曙光， 心中闪烁着♪
♪You're the final answer, no regrets, no woes♪
♪你就是最终的答案， 无悔无忧♪
♪My unspoken words are depicted in scrolls♪
♪我未说出口的话 被描绘成卷轴♪
♪One after another♪
♪一个又一个♪
(The horse leaped over the stream this morning.)
（今天早上，这匹马跳过了小溪 。）
(Upon smelling the fragrance)
（闻到香味后）
(and coming across a wild cinnamon tree.)
（并遇到 一棵野生肉桂树。）
(With its hidden aroma drifting in the air,)
（空气中飘荡着隐秘的香气，）
(I enjoyed this sight myself with deep regret.)
（我自己也很欣赏这一景象， 但也深感遗憾。）
(Then, I picked several flower buds)
（然后，我摘了几个花蕾）
(to create a fragrant sachet,)
（制作香袋，）
(hoping we could enjoy it together another day.)
（希望改天我们能一起享受。）
♪I'm willing to abandon this world for you♪
♪我愿意 为了你放弃这个世界♪
♪No regrets in this lifetime♪
♪此生无悔♪
Lieutenant He!
何中尉！
Lieutenant He, I've been looking for you.
何中尉，我一直在找你。
So here you are.
所以你在这里。
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没有什么。
I just want to ask
我只是想问
if you're replying to his letter today.
如果你今天回复他的信。
Are you worried that Xie Chang'er
你担心谢嫦儿吗
is in a rush again?
又很着急吗？
No.
不。
I made an appointment with him
我和他约好了
that Luoyang would be our meeting point
洛阳将是我们的见面地点
to exchange letters.
来交换信件。
Luoyang as the meeting point?
洛阳作为集合地点？
Was it your idea
这是你的主意吗
or Xie Chang'er's idea?
or Xie Chang'er's idea?
Xie Chang'er said,
Xie Chang'er said,
it was Mister Shiqi who suggested
是石其先生提议的
meeting in Luoyang
meeting in Luoyang
to make it easier to find each other
为了更容易找到对方
while marching.
行军时。
Xie Chang'er is the one
谢嫦儿就是那个
who delivers messages between the two armies.
谁在两军之间传递信息。
By keeping track of when he arrives
通过跟踪他到达的时间
and calculating
并计算
the speed of the horses,
马匹的速度，
it's quite easy to figure out
很容易弄清楚
where the Zhenxi Army is currently heading.
镇西军 目前所在的地方。
What?
什么？
Li Ni is so cunning.
李妮真是太狡猾了。
Lieutenant He, only you
何中尉 只有你
could guess
可以猜到
all his intricate thoughts and intentions.
他所有复杂的想法 和意图。
Does that mean
这是否意味着
I'm cunning too?
我也很狡猾吗？
No,
不，
yours is wisdom.
你的就是智慧。
So are you going to reply to his letter?
那么你要回复他的信吗？
I don't know yet.
我还不知道。
What do you mean you don't know?
你不知道是什么意思？
Are you going to reply to him?
你要回复他吗？
Well, I really don't know.
嗯，我真的不知道。
Well, will you write it?
嗯，你会写吗？
Come on, write it.
来吧，写一下。
Someone went inside your tent.
有人走进你的帐篷。
Taozi, come.
桃子，怎么样。
Let's take a walk.
我们去溜达一下。
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
are we not going in to catch that spy red-handed?
我们不去 当场抓获那个间谍吗？
No matter.
不管。
Communicating with Li Ni using letters
与李妮书信交流
was meant to lure out this spy.
是为了引诱这个间谍。
Since they fell for it and acted foolish again,
既然他们又上当了 ，又犯了傻事，
then let them be.
那就随他们去吧。
Master,
掌握，
this is the letter Li Ni wrote to Lieutenant He.
这是李妮写给何中尉的信。
I thought of a way
我想到了一个办法
and copied it word by word.
并逐字逐句地抄写下来。
"I found combining dried nuts with preserved fruits
“我发现将干坚果 与蜜饯结合起来
enhances the flavor?
增强风味？
But trying them together now..."
但现在尝试将它们放在一起......”
What's this?
这是什么？
In my opinion,
在我看来，
Li Ni and Lieutenant He
Li Ni and Lieutenant He
are both shrewd individuals.
都是精明的人。
This letter appears normal on the surface.
这封信表面上看起来很正常。
But it contains secret codes
但它包含秘密代码
with hidden messages.
带有隐藏消息。
That's why Lieutenant He
这就是为什么何中尉
didn't hide the letter in some hidden place.
没有把信藏 在某个隐蔽的地方。
She just left it out in the open
她只是把它放在公开的地方
without being afraid of it being seen.
而不害怕被看到。
The phrase about combining dried nuts and preserved fruits together
关于干果和果脯结合在一起的短语
must be their secret code.
一定是他们的密码。
That makes sense.
这就说得通了。
How about we get someone
我们找个人怎么样
to decipher this letter?
破译这封信？
Of course.
当然。
(Since our parting,)
（自从我们分手后，）
(just a few days have passed, yet it feels like years.)
（虽然才过去几天， 但感觉却像过了好几年一样。）
(I have never felt like this before.)
（我以前从未有过这样的感觉。）
(How I miss you so.)
（我多么想念你啊。）
(At sunset, I saw some plump common water frogs.)
（日落时分，我看到了一些肥硕的 普通水蛙。）
(I caught a few of them and roasted them.)
（我抓了一些 并烤了它们。）
(Too bad the fire was too intense,)
（可惜火太猛了）
(and they got slightly burnt.)
（它们被轻微烧伤了。）
(Letters)
（信件）
Master!
掌握！
After a lot of effort,
经过一番努力，
we've finally figured out the secret behind the communication
我们终于找到了 沟通背后的秘密
between Lieutenant He and Li Ni.
何中尉和李妮之间。
Go on.
继续。
Upon leaving Laolan Pass, Li Ni, Imperial Grandson,
离开老兰关后， 皇孙李妮，
has always excelled in long-distance raids,
一直 在远距离突袭方面表现出色，
using deception and diversion to create chaos.
利用欺骗 和转移注意力来制造混乱。
This time,
这次，
he left Luoyang voluntarily.
他自愿离开洛阳。
I'm sure he's using the same tactic.
我确信他也在使用同样的策略。
You have a point.
你有一定道理。
Keep going.
继续前进。
Master Cui, please take a look.
请崔老师看一下。
This letter is the most recent letter that Lieutenant He received.
这封信是何中尉最近收到的一封信。
The phrase "caught a few"
一句话“抓到了一些”
typically refers
通常指的是
to a target staying by the lakeside.
到湖边的目标。
By breaking down the phrase,
通过分解这个短语，
doesn't it suggest an encircling strategy?
这不是暗示了 包围战略吗？
Then who's the target by the lakeside?
那么湖边的目标是谁呢？
Now, isn't it a coincidence
现在看来，这难道不是巧合吗？
that our army happened to have passed by a lake
我们的军队恰好 经过一个湖
and is now located by the lakeside?
现在位于湖边？
If nothing goes wrong,
如果不出什么问题的话
at sunset today,
今天日落时分，
the Zhenxi Army will likely send someone to join Lieutenant He,
镇西军很可能会派人 去和何中尉会合，
coordinating an ambush against our forces.
协调伏击 我们的部队。
Master,
掌握，
why not inform the commander of this now?
为什么不 现在就通知指挥官呢？
Then, we could set an ambush.
那么我们就可以设下埋伏了。
If we successfully repel the Zhenxi Army,
如果成功击退 镇西军
it would be a significant achievement.
这将是一项重大成就。
Indeed.
的确。
You fools!
你们这些傻瓜！
Master, calm down.
师父，冷静点。
Answer me.
回答我。
Everyone knows that Li Ni is trying to breach Tong Pass.
所有人都知道，李妮 想要攻破潼关。
How can he simultaneously launch an attack on us?
他怎么能同时 向我们发起攻击呢？
Uh...
呃...
It has already passed sunset.
已经过了日落。
So, where is Li Ni?
那么，李妮在哪里呢？
Answer me!
回答我！
Master.
掌握。
Oh, Master.
哦，师父。
Useless bunch!
一群没用的！
- What a useless bunch! - Please, Master.
——一群没用的家伙！ - 拜托了，主人。
Get lost.
迷路。
I said, get lost!
我说，滚吧！
Yes.
是的。
We'll take our leave.
我们就告辞了
Where did you get these?
你从哪里得到这些？
Cui Li has been ordering his men to monitor Lieutenant He.
崔立一直在命令手下 监视何中尉。
These are the letters he copied secretly.
这些是他秘密抄写的信 。
I obtained these
我得到了这些
from Cui Li's tent.
从崔莉的帐篷里传来。
But Lieutenant He knew
但何中尉知道
about Cui Li's action.
关于崔莉的举动。
But she didn't pursue it.
但她并没有追究。
Master, calm down.
师父，冷静点。
I just remembered
我刚想起来
something important.
一些重要的事情。
Previously, Lieutenant He used a letter
此前，何中尉用过一封信
to set us up.
来安排我们。
This reminds me
这让我想起
of how coincident it was.
多么巧合。
It happened
它发生了
after you met Pei Yuan.
遇见裴媛之后。
Are you saying
你是说
that after I met with Pei Yuan,
当我遇见裴媛之后
he disclosed the plan to Lieutenant He?
他把这个计划透露给何中尉了？
The two collaborated to lure me in?
两人联手引诱我？
But shouldn't we
但我们不应该
be on the same side
站在同一边
when it comes to killing Cui Lin?
什么时候杀崔琳？
If you want His Highness's letter,
如果你想要殿下的信
it depends on whether you can kill Cui Lin.
就看 你能不能杀掉崔琳了。
It appears Li Ni has a close relationship
看来 李妮关系密切
with Lieutenant He.
与何中尉。
Otherwise,
否则，
why would he share
他为什么要分享
such classified information with her?
跟她有这么机密的信息？
I previously considered
我之前考虑过
using Li Ni's hand to eliminate Lieutenant He.
借李妮之手消灭何中尉。
But now it seems
但现在看来
not only he won't assist us,
他不仅不会帮助我们，
but he'll also be against me.
但他也会反对我。
Master, be patient.
大师，请耐心等待。
Those defending Luoyang
Those defending Luoyang
are Li Ni's two older brothers,
是李妮的两个哥哥，
Li Jun and Li Lai.
Li Jun and Li Lai.
They have always been at odds with him.
他们一直与他不和。
Why don't we join forces with them?
我们为什么不和他们联手呢？
This way,
这边走，
we can resolve our issue of having no military authority.
我们可以解决没有军事权威的问题。
Excellent idea.
好主意。
(Tong Pass is a formidable stronghold, easy to defend and difficult to attack.)
（潼关是重镇， 易守难攻。）
(Li Ni led his army and they fought for six days.)
（李尼率军 激战六天。）
(With Pei Yuan leading the charge,)
（裴源带头，）
(they finally captured Tong Pass.)
（他们终于攻克了潼关。）
Congratulations, Your Highness.
恭喜您，殿下。
After the Zhenxi Army recaptured Dongdu,
镇西军收复东都后，
they captured Tong Pass not long after that.
不久，他们就占领了潼关。
Tong Pass?
通关？
That means they're not far
这意味着他们并不遥远
from Xichang anymore.
不再是西昌人了
Yes, Your Highness.
是的殿下。
They're getting close
他们正在接近
to Xichang.
to Xichang.
Li Ni chose not to contend with his older brothers
李妮选择不 与哥哥抗衡
and directly abandoned Luoyang.
并直接放弃了洛阳。
He launched a surprise attack on Tong Pass, which is 500 li away.
他对五百里外的潼关发起奇袭。
A bad bamboo can sometimes yield good shoots.
坏竹有时也能 长出好芽。
Lord Liang
Lord Liang
sure has a capable son.
肯定有一个能干的儿子。
Well, never mind that.
好吧，别介意。
Lord Liang's three sons
梁王的三个儿子
are now close by.
现在就在附近。
As their father,
作为他们的父亲，
he has been held up in the capital for a long time.
他已经被困在京城 很久了。
It's time for him to write letters to his sons.
现在是他 给儿子们写信的时候了。
Sit.
坐。
Shiqi, how did the battle go?
十七，战斗进行得怎么样了？
The overall situation is settled.
总体局势已定。
Don't pursue a desperate foe.
不要追击绝望的敌人。
What about you?
你呢？
Are you all right?
你没事儿吧？
These are just flesh injuries.
这些只是皮肉之伤。
Great.
伟大的。
After battling hard for so long,
经过这么长时间的艰苦奋斗，
we've finally taken Tong Pass.
我们终于攻克了潼关。
My father said
我父亲说
Tong Pass is known as the strongest stronghold.
潼关被誉为 最强据点。
Since the founding of the nation,
建国以来，
no army has been able to capture it.
没有任何军队能够占领它。
In the future,
将来，
the Zhenxi Army can leave its mark in the annals of imperial history.
镇西军能够 在帝国史册上留下浓墨重彩的一笔。
Now, the situation has shifted from attack to defense.
现在，局势已由 攻转为守。
So after this,
所以在这之后，
you'll only have to worry
你只需要担心
about how to defend Tong Pass.
关于如何防守潼关。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
is there another Zhenxi Army in this world?
这世上还有镇西军吗？
There's also no other Shiqi in this world.
这世上也没有第二个十七了。
Then, the world doesn't have
那么，世界上就没有
another courageous Pei Yuan.
另一个勇敢的裴源。
Don't flatter me.
别阿谀奉承我。
But Shiqi,
But Shiqi,
I have a question.
我有个问题。
You know it's impossible.
你知道这是不可能的。
Why did you write letters
你为什么写信
to Lord Kuaiji and Lord Linzi,
to Lord Kuaiji and Lord Linzi,
asking them to jointly encircle Xichang?
让他们联合围剿西昌？
My two older brothers are as stubborn as mules
我的两个哥哥 像骡子一样顽固
from being spoiled by my father.
免得被我父亲宠坏了。
If you want to go west,
如果你想去西边，
they will insist on going east.
他们将坚持向东走。
I don't want them to act rashly and send troops
我不希望他们 轻举妄动，出兵
to cause trouble to fight over merits
争功夺利
at a critical moment like this.
在这样的关键时刻。
So of course, I have to write letters to them to join the encirclement.
所以我当然要写信 给他们加入包围圈。
When I do this,
当我这样做时，
they're less likely to listen to me,
他们不太可能听我的话
and naturally remain idle,
自然就闲着，
without taking any action.
不采取任何行动。
This is called reverse psychology.
这就是所谓的逆反心理。
Saying one thing but doing the opposite.
说的是一套，做的却是相反的。
(Luoyang)
（洛阳）
(Recipient, Brother.)
（收件人，兄弟。）
(Lord Linzi, Li Jun)
(Lord Linzi, Li Jun)
(Please lead the troops. I'll siege and recapture the capital.)
（请带兵，我来围攻 ，夺回京城。）
(Lord Kuaiji, Li Lai)
(Lord Kuaiji, Li Lai)
Jun, what did he write in the letter?
君，他信里写了什么？
Read it yourself.
你自己读一下吧。
Li Ni has captured Tong Pass.
李泥攻克了潼关。
He wants us
他想要我们
to deploy troops to surround Xichang?
出兵包围西昌？
Jun, what is he...
俊，他是什么……
Li Ni dares
李妮敢
to order us around
对我们发号施令
by relying on his achievement
凭借他的成就
in taking Tong Pass!
攻克潼关！
Jun, being ordered around is one thing.
君，被命令是一回事。
But deploying troops to surround Xichang
而是调兵围攻西昌
is a serious matter.
是一件严重的事情。
I'm afraid he intends to use our troops
恐怕他打算动用我们的军队
to help him achieve his goals.
帮助他实现他的目标。
I've long known
我早就知道
that Li Ni is treacherous.
说李妮奸诈。
We can't
我们不能
let his plans succeed.
让他的计划成功。
Jun,
君，
didn't Cui Li of the Cui Army
崔军的崔立不是吗？
send a messenger here a few days ago?
几天前派了使者来这里？
You mean...
你的意思是...
Jun,
君，
I think
我认为
we can lend troops to Cui Li
我们可以借兵给崔立
because he's lending the troops to kill Cui Lin
因为他借兵 去杀崔琳
and put the blame on Li Ni.
并将责任归咎于李妮。
That way,
那样，
he'll become
他会成为
a sharp blade
锋利的刀片
in your hands.
在你手中。
Young Master.
少爷。
You have returned.
你回来了。
It must be a rough journey.
这一定是一段艰难的旅程。
How is Father's health?
父亲的健康状况如何？
Great General is doing well.
大将军过得很好。
But when he heard Young Master Cui Li came here without permission
可当他听说崔立少爷 擅自来到这里的时候
and interfered with military affairs,
并干涉军事事务，
he was furious
他很生气
and ordered me to bring the command badge to you.
并命令我 把指挥徽章带给你。
This is great.
这很棒。
With this command badge,
有了这个指挥徽章，
I can order Cui Li back to Yingzhou.
我可以命崔立回瀛州。
Then I no longer have to worry about him causing trouble.
这样我就再也不用担心 他惹麻烦了。
I can't believe
我不敢相信
Cui Lin resorted to all means to obtain Uncle's command badge
崔琳使出浑身解数， 想要得到叔叔的指挥徽章
to order me to depart back to Yingzhou
命我回瀛州
and not to follow the main army.
并且不跟随主力部队。
Cui Lin, you jerk.
Cui Lin, you jerk.
Am I that dreadful to you
我对你来说有那么可怕吗
that you try every means to transfer me away?
你千方百计 要把我转移走吗？
Master, calm down.
师父，冷静点。
We have received a reply from Luoyang.
我们已收到洛阳方面的回复。
Why don't we read what it says?
我们为什么不读一下它说的内容呢？
(Grant the title of Grand General Weiyang)
（授予 未央大将军称号）
Master, what does it say?
师父，这句话怎么说呢？
Li Jun has agreed to send troops
李军已同意出兵
to help me kill Cui Lin.
帮我杀了崔琳。
Once I succeed,
一旦我成功了，
he'll appoint me as Great General Weiyang.
他会任命我 为未央大将军。
Congratulations, Master.
恭喜师父。
Congratulations, Great General.
恭喜你，伟大的将军。
As long as Cui Lin is dead,
只要崔琳死了，
I will command
我会指挥
the Cui Army rightfully.
崔军理所应当。
At that time,
当时，
we can blame Li Ni
我们可以责怪李妮
for everything.
对于一切。
Two birds with one stone.
一石二鸟。
Absolutely flawless.
绝对完美无缺。
No wonder it was so difficult to conquer this place.
难怪 要征服这个地方如此困难。
Look at the city walls
看看城墙
and the surrounding terrain.
以及周围的地形。
It's truly a fortress
这确实是一座堡垒
that's hard to breach.
这是很难打破的。
When we tried to capture it, it was tough.
当我们试图捕捉它时， 这很困难。
But now that our roles have switched to defense,
但现在我们的角色已经转变 为防守，
these natural defenses
这些自然防御
are indeed advantageous.
确实有优势。
It is, isn't it?
是的，不是吗？
If Laolan Pass had half of this natural advantage,
如果老兰关有一半 这样的天然优势，
we wouldn't need
我们不需要
so many troops to defend it.
这么多军队来保卫它。
Is it another letter?
是另一封信吗？
Mister Shiqi,
Mister Shiqi,
you must be eagerly awaiting news.
你一定正在焦急地等待消息。
(Tong Pass)
（通关）
Report!
报告！
An envoy from Xichang has arrived!
西昌使者来了！
Grand Governor sent me to convey his order.
大督派我 传达他的命令。
The Zhenxi Army must withdraw from Tong Pass within three days.
镇西军必须在三天内撤出潼关。
Outrageous!
太离谱了！
Did Sun Jing send you here to die?
孙靖派你来这里送死的吗？
General Pei Yuan.
General Pei Yuan.
Since I dared to come,
既然我敢来，
I'm not afraid of losing my life.
我不怕失去生命。
Also, there's a letter from Lord Liang
还有梁王的一封信
for you.
为你。
What if I insist on not withdrawing the troops?
如果我坚持 不撤军怎么办？
If you don't withdraw,
如果不退的话
then three days from now at noon,
然后三天后的中午，
Your Highness should prepare mourning attire
殿下 应该准备丧服
to mourn Lord Liang.
悼念梁公。
I suppose my father
我想我的父亲
must have written three letters.
一定写了三个字母。
The other two have already been sent to Luoyang
另外两人 已被送往洛阳
for my two brothers, right?
为了我的两个兄弟，对吗？
Yes.
是的。
I wonder,
我想知道，
compared to Your Highness and your brothers,
与殿下和您的兄弟相比，
which one of you is more filial?
你们谁更孝顺？
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
you still haven't finished these dried nuts?
你还没吃完 这些干坚果吗？
These were quite popular in Dongdu at that time,
这些当时在东都很流行，
and people said they were delicious.
人们说它们很好吃。
Many people rushed to buy them.
许多人争相购买。
You're good at remembering all these details.
你很擅长记住 所有这些细节。
Originally,
起初，
everyone just ate dried nuts and kernels.
每个人都只吃干坚果 和果仁。
But you prefer
但你更喜欢
eating them with preserved fruits.
与蜜饯一起吃。
How could I not remember something like that?
我怎么会不记得 这样的事情呢？
Moreover, kernels are indeed crispy and fill the stomach,
而且，果仁确实酥脆 ，填饱肚子，
quite delicious.
相当好吃。
But,
但，
it's been days now,
已经过去好几天了
and Tong Pass
和通关
hasn't sent a single letter.
一封信也没寄出。
Are you worried about a certain someone
你是否担心某个人
or Tong Pass?
还是通关？
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
I'm talking about serious matters.
我正在谈论严肃的事情。
Perhaps something has happened in the capital.
或许，京城里发生了什么事。
So he might not have the time to write letters.
所以他可能没有时间 写信。
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
who are you talking about?
你在说谁？
Who is he?
他是谁？
Even dried nuts
甚至干坚果
can't stop you from talking.
无法阻止你说话。
All right, I'll stop.
好吧，我停下来。
But who is he?
但他是谁？
Shiqi, an urgent report from Luoyang.
Shiqi, an urgent report from Luoyang.
Lord Linzi and Lord Kuaiji
Lord Linzi and Lord Kuaiji
have already decided to withdraw their troops from Luoyang.
已经决定 从洛阳撤军。
(No movement from the enemy.)
（敌人没有任何动静。）
My two brothers have always been filial
我的两个兄弟一向很孝顺
(Provisions are being transported) since they were young.
（给养） 从小就这样。
It's no wonder
这也难怪
my father has always cherished them.
我父亲一直很珍惜它们。
Luoyang was originally an advantage
洛阳本来就是优势
they took from you.
他们从你那里夺走了。
They naturally won't feel the pinch.
他们自然不会感觉到压力。
But now,
但现在，
we're in a difficult situation.
我们的处境很困难。
We absolutely cannot let go of Tong Pass.
我们绝对不能放过通关。
If Luoyang falls,
如果洛阳失守，
our army will be cut off.
我们的军队将被切断。
But Sun Jing
但孙静
is truly ruthless.
真是无情。
If we don't withdraw the troops,
如果我们不撤军
he might really harm Lord Liang.
他说不定真的会害梁王。
Shiqi, what do we do?
诗琪，我们该怎么办？
Shiqi!
Shiqi!
From the emperor to the common people,
从皇帝 到百姓，
we all believe in the importance of being filial.
我们都相信 孝顺的重要性。
If we don't withdraw the troops,
如果我们不撤军
Sun Jing might really kill Lord Liang.
孙敬说不定真的会杀了梁王。
When that happens,
当这种情况发生时，
there will be an uproar.
将会引起轩然大波。
Those senior officials and army loyalists
那些高级官员和军队的忠诚者
will all turn against us.
都会反对我们。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
what should we do now?
我们现在应该做什么？
Miss, you can't go.
小姐，你不能走。
If you go,
如果你走的话，
you'll be walking into a death trap.
你将会走进死亡陷阱。
Qiucui,
Qiucui,
please don't stop me.
请不要阻止我。
I've never been favored
我从来没有被宠过
by my parents at home.
我的父母在家里。
I almost lost my life in Bingzhou.
我在并州差点丢了性命。
If it weren't for Li Ni saving me,
如果不是李妮救了我
I might have become
我可能已经成为
a mound of earth by now.
现在已经是一堆土了。
When he saved me,
当他救我的时候，
he seemed like a god descending from heaven.
他就像一个从天而降的神 。
At that moment, I thought,
那一刻我想，
perhaps he was the one I'd been waiting for.
也许他就是我一直在等待的人。
To repay him,
为了报答他，
I'm willing to give everything, even my life.
我愿意付出一切， 甚至生命。
But Miss,
不过小姐，
you've had a tough life from a young age.
你从小就过着艰苦的生活。
If you really lose your life because of this,
如果你真的因此失去了生命
I'm afraid there won't be anyone left who truly cares about you.
恐怕再也没有一个 真正关心你的人了。
Miss,
错过，
I want to go with you and make it back to Xichang alive.
我想和你一起活着 回到西昌。
Li Ni captured Luoyang
Li Ni captured Luoyang
and Tong Pass after.
后又通关。
He advanced like the raging wind,
他如疾风般前行，
showing he was not an ordinary man.
说明他不是一个普通人。
He'll have a bright future.
他将会有一个光明的未来。
He's a person who values loyalty and righteousness.
他是一个重义重义的人 。
If I help him in times of danger,
如果我在他遇到危险的时候帮助他，
he'll surely remember
他一定会记得
and repay me with gratitude.
并报答我的感激之情。
If I can help him now,
如果我现在能帮助他的话
do I have to worry
我需要担心吗
about having no place here?
关于这里没有地方？
If I don't strive now, when should I?
如果我现在不努力，更待何时呢？
Miss,
错过，
why do you suddenly
你为什么突然
seem like a different person?
看起来像另一个人？
Before, you never sought to compete or vie for anything.
以前，你从未试图竞争 或争夺任何东西。
Sometimes, when servants were disrespectful to you,
有时，当仆人 对你不敬时，
you wouldn't allow me to stand up for you.
你不允许我 为你挺身而出。
Qiucui,
Qiucui,
I didn't strive
我没有努力
because I didn't have the strength
因为我没有力气
or the opportunity to compete.
或竞争的机会。
So why bother if it's in vain?
既然都是徒劳，那又何必费心呢？
In the future,
将来，
you'll be my trusted confidant.
你将成为我值得信赖的知己。
You must also learn
你还必须学习
to assess situations
评估情况
and choose when to act wisely.
并选择何时明智地采取行动。
That's what smart people do.
这就是聪明人所做的。
Greetings, General.
您好，将军。
Greetings, General Pei Yuan.
裴远将军，您好。
Miss Gu, no need to be formal.
顾小姐，不用太正式。
I have a confidential matter
我有一件机密的事
to discuss with you.
与您讨论。
Miss Gu, please speak.
顾小姐请发言。
I heard Sun Jing
听说孙静
uses Lord Liang to threaten you.
用梁王来威胁你。
I'm willing to go to Xichang
我愿意去西昌
to act on your behalf
代表您行事
and find a way to rescue Lord Liang.
并想办法营救梁王。
Do you have any plans?
你有什么计划吗？
In the capital, many influential and loyal families
京城里， 有许多有影响力、忠心耿耿的家族。
still support the country.
还是支持国家的。
However, Sun Jing is too powerful.
不过，孙靖实在是太强大了。
So they dare not speak out.
所以他们不敢说出来。
Please provide a token to me.
请提供一个令牌给我。
When I return to the capital,
当我回到首都时，
in your name,
以你的名义，
I'll contact these noble families in secret,
我会秘密联系这些贵族，
and bribe the palace guards.
并贿赂宫廷守卫。
Perhaps, by using a strategic approach, we might be able to rescue Lord Liang.
或许，我们用计谋， 或许能够救出梁王。
No,
不，
it's too risky.
太冒险了。
If Sun Jing finds out,
如果孙静知道的话
or if someone betrays you,
或者如果有人背叛你，
it could cost you your life and implicate...
它可能会夺去你的生命并牵连...
I'm not afraid of death.
我不怕死。
If I die for righteousness,
如果我为正义而死，
it would be an honorable death.
这将是一种光荣的死亡。
Even my father,
就连我的父亲，
I'm sure you know
我确定你知道
that he won't yield to that traitor, Sun Jing.
他不会屈服于 孙靖这个叛徒。
He will surely agree with my decision.
他一定会同意我的决定。
Thank you for your loyalty, Miss Gu.
谢谢你的忠诚，顾小姐。
I've already made an arrangement in the capital.
我已经在京城做好了安排。
So you can rest assured.
所以你可以放心。
Jin'niang,
Jin'niang,
did you say this letter
你说这封信吗
was placed on the table,
被放在桌子上，
but you don't know who delivered it?
但你不知道是谁送的？
Your Highness,
殿下，
could it be a trap set by Grand Governor?
难道是大总督设下的陷阱 ？
No, it doesn't look like it.
不，看起来不像。
This letter is full of cryptic words.
这封信充满了晦涩难懂的字眼。
This letter is full of cryptic messages.
这封信充满了神秘的信息。
But I understand
但是我明白
what he's asking for.
他在要求什么。
I think
我认为
Li Ni wants to join forces with me.
李妮想和我联手。
He must have been planning this for a long time
他肯定已经计划了 很长时间了
and finally had the confidence to rescue Lord Liang.
终于有了信心 去营救梁王。
Your Highness, do we...
殿下，我们……
Of course, we'll help him.
当然，我们会帮助他。
Do as what was written in the letter.
按照信中写的去做。
Move the orchid under the window.
把兰花移到窗户下面。
Yes, Your Highness.
是的殿下。
This is great, Miss.
这太棒了，小姐。
You don't need to take risks by going to Xichang anymore.
你不用 再去西昌冒险了。
His Highness will surely have a way to rescue Lord Liang.
殿下一定有办法 救梁王。
Although he hasn't explicitly revealed the plan to me,
虽然他还没有明确 向我透露这个计划，
through this incident,
通过这次事件，
I have become someone he trusts.
我已经成为他信任的人了。
Miss, are you planning...
小姐，你打算...
Li Ni and Lieutenant He of the Cui Army
李妮与崔军何中尉
often have close contacts.
经常有密切接触。
They seem to share a romantic connection.
他们似乎有着 浪漫的联系。
It's a good thing the Cui Army has returned to Yingzhou.
崔军回到颍州，这是好事。
So they'll be far apart.
所以他们会分开很远。
If I'm someone he trusts,
如果我是他信任的人
I'll naturally find a way
我自然会找到办法
to create some distance between him and Lieutenant He.
拉开 他和何中尉之间的距离。
If you could marry His Highness,
如果你能嫁给殿下
it would be great.
这会很棒。
Then, no one in the mansion would dare to look down on you.
到时候，府里 就没人敢瞧不起你了。
But it's too early to talk about this now.
但现在谈论这个还为时过早。
I wonder if His Highness will be able
不知道殿下能不能
to rescue Lord Liang this time.
这次去救梁王。
To be honest,
说实话，
whether or not Lord Liang can be rescued
梁公能否 获救
is entirely beneficial
是完全有益的
for Li Ni.
为了李妮。
Miss,
错过，
I don't understand.
我不明白。
If he successfully rescues Lord Liang,
如果他成功救出梁王，
it would naturally be great.
那自然就太好了。
After that, Li Ni would have unrestricted military power.
从此，李霓将拥有不受限制的 军事权力。
If he failed to rescue Lord Liang,
如果他没能救出梁王，
and Lord Liang was killed by Sun Jing.
梁公被孙敬所杀。
Even in his grief,
即使在他悲伤的时候，
he won't need to fear consequences.
他不需要担心后果。
Even if there is public criticism,
即使有舆论批评，
as long as Li Ni holds military authority,
只要李妮 掌握着军事权力，
who will dare to blame Li Ni in the future?
以后谁还敢怪罪李妮？
Since Li Ni likes intelligent people,
由于李妮喜欢聪明的人，
I don't need to hide my cleverness
我不需要隐藏我的聪明
in front of him.
在他前面。
Do you think
你认为
Li Ni will withdraw from Tong Pass
李妮将退出潼关
like his brothers?
像他的兄弟们一样？
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
If a battle is lost,
如果一场战斗失败了，
they can make a comeback.
他们可以东山再起。
But once people's trust is lost,
但一旦失去人们的信任
it's hard to get it back.
很难把它找回来。
His brothers
他的兄弟们
are already leaving Luoyang.
已经离开洛阳了。
If Li Ni doesn't move,
如果李妮不动的话
he'll be the subject of criticism.
他将成为批评的对象。
I think he'll withdraw.
我想他会退出。
Li Ni is a clever schemer.
李妮是一个聪明的阴谋家。
He likely already has a plan to rescue Lord Liang.
他大概已经有了营救梁王的计划了。
Sun Jing is vigilant in guarding Lord Liang.
孙敬警惕 地守护着梁公。
It won't be easy to rescue him.
想要救他并不容易。
So, he needs to think carefully and come up with a plan.
所以，他需要仔细思考 ，制定一个计划。
Plus, he needs favorable timing, location, and cooperation.
另外，他还需要有利的天时、 地利、配合。
But I think Li Ni
但我觉得李妮
already has an arrangement
已经有安排
for everything.
对于一切。
Favorable timing, location, and cooperation?
有利的时间、 地点和合作？
What is considered favorable timing,
什么叫天时、 地利、合作？
Taozi,
Taozi,
do you still remember
你还记得吗
the medicine you formulated for him?
你给他配的药？
Lieutenant He!
何中尉！
Lieutenant He,
何中尉，
urgent report from Yingzhou.
瀛州紧急报告。
Young Master asked you to return to discuss this matter.
少爷让你回去 商量这件事。
♪If I forget the fleeting of time♪
♪如果我忘记了转瞬即逝的时光♪
♪Waiting for memories♪
♪等待回忆♪
♪To shatter and sink♪
♪破碎并沉没♪
♪The emotional scars in your heart♪
♪你心中的情感伤痕♪
♪Are the entanglement♪
♪是纠缠♪
♪I find hard to let go of♪
♪我发现很难放手♪
♪If longing is not forgotten♪
♪如果没有忘记渴望的话♪
♪I long to return to the very first moment♪
♪我渴望回到 最初的那一刻♪
♪The affection we had in our fateful situation♪
♪我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪How I wish to keep it for you♪
♪我多么想为你保留它♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promises we made♪
♪我们的约定♪
♪Even if this love hurts me♪
♪即使这份爱让我受伤♪
♪I'll continue living for you♪
♪我会继续为你而活♪
♪Holding onto the memories♪
♪紧紧抓住回忆♪
♪Waiting is my persistence♪
♪等待是我的坚持♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪我对你的承诺♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪尽管违背命运♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪我不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪The promise I made to you♪
♪我对你的承诺♪
♪Despite going against fate♪
♪尽管违背命运♪
♪I have no regrets loving you♪
♪我不后悔爱你♪
♪I'm willing to sacrifice for you♪
♪我愿意为你牺牲♪
♪As I wait for your answer♪
♪等待你的答复♪